[Music]
i went to the post this morning and
picked up some letters from some of you
and spent the morning reading them each
one is so touching and i often find
myself reflecting on your words and
stories for the rest of the day
one wonderful viewer in particular asked
me how i've developed confidence
considering i make videos and have
accepted the positive and negative
criticism that entails
they also asked how i combat allergies
this time of year and
unfortunately that is a constant battle
i have yet to find a lasting solution
for
[Music]
i considered myself a very quiet and
nervous child
but despite it i did really enjoy my own
company and had an inner confidence in
myself
even though i was very shy around other
people then i turned 18 and was living
with my family
on a naval base in italy i wanted to
study literature nearby
and so i started my degree in ireland
and later finished it in the states
this was a wonderful experience but also
difficult
i'd always lived with my family and the
sudden change was a lot to take in
everyone said i'd stop missing them in
time but that never changed
[Music]
do
i was in a very vulnerable position for
those years of learning how to be an
adult
and unfortunately it caused me to be a
poor judge of character
i was lonely and desperate for anyone
who could make me feel safe
in a world that felt suddenly so chaotic
and unfortunately that desperation
attracted people with the opposite
intention
i was blind to the difference between
someone who wants support
and help and someone who wants to
control and suppress
who you are i was so young and i say
that knowing i still
am but it's incredible how certain
experiences give you a completely new
perspective
on life as naive and unbelievable as it
sounds i truly could not believe that
someone would intentionally be
unkind or that people don't necessarily
want to change that about themselves
so i believe the excuses and apologies
always ready to forgive and forget to
this day i still don't understand people
who do cruel things
and honestly i think i never will
in retrospect i learned a lot i realized
that i had to become stronger and
assertive
and not agree with things just to be
agreeable
i also had to distance myself from
people who did not consider
my safety or well-being
[Music]
of course i will not give those people
the compliment of saying that my
experience with them led me to become
confident because that is not true
i'm on a journey of self-love and
confidence despite them
i had to be brave and make my own
decisions instead of letting someone
else take over
i had to learn to be at peace with the
body and mind and soul
that was given to me to let go of
wishing things were different
to treat my mistakes with gentle
understanding
lastly i decided that past experiences
wouldn't keep me from loving again
and being open to the fear that comes
with that
i'm happy to say that i now have someone
in my life that if i could describe in
two words
it would be kind and gentle
someone who wants to compliment you not
control you
and that's all i ever really wanted and
needed
with an unshakable foundation of love
and respect
everything else slowly falls into place
[Music]
so
do
[Music]
so
easy
as for making these videos i suppose i
have
i guess the confidence to share
not because i am not nervous about
putting my videos out there i always am
nervous every time i upload
but i know that the power of genuine
human connection
is so much more meaningful and important
than
anything else and any negative feedback
or
any type of judgment that might
make you second-guess what you're trying
to do i also
am an artist and i think it's very
important to
develop the confidence and the belief in
what you're doing
and share it there isn't any reason that
you should
tolerate anything less than respect from
others words have as much power over you
as you allow them to have there have
been moments where i've been very
intimidated about
uploading a video or continuing with
this channel and there's been times i
just
didn't know what to do but even though
i've sometimes been unsure
at the end of the day i know what i'm
trying to do and that
keeps me wanting to grow and to be a
little more confident every day
i suppose that whenever you put yourself
out there you will get mixed reactions
and if you can be at peace with that and
know that your
intentions are just to be to add
something
of value to the world then
it's okay it's okay that not everyone
will understand who you are or where
you're coming from
as long as you know that what you're
trying to do is something you believe in
and something of value and something
that might help people
i hope that what i talked about in
today's video isn't
too sad or or upsetting i
i really want it to feel hopeful
thank you all for listening i kind of
rambled on today
i um was in kind of a talkative mood
i did something to my knee while running
through the field and i don't know what
i did but it kind of put me out for
a day so i'm just relaxing here and i'm
probably going to read some books
so i hope you all have a wonderful day
or night
sending you my love bye
are you sure you want to be part of this
shot
it's recording there's no going back
this is the best way to do it laying
down like this get the right angle oh my
gosh